<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
============LICENSE_START=======================================================
Copyright (C) 2018-2019 Sven van der Meer. All rights reserved.
================================================================================
This file is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License
Full license text at https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/legalcode

SPDX-License-Identifier: CC-BY-SA-4.0
============LICENSE_END=========================================================

@author Sven van der Meer (vdmeer.sven@mykolab.com)

-->

<document>

    <properties>
        <title>Research Experience</title>
        <author email="vdmeer dot sven at mykolab dot com">Sven van der Meer</author>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="Research Experience">

            <table>
                <tr>
                    <td>1995 – 1996</td>
                    <td>
                        Research Student, Institute for Open Communication Systems, GMD FOKUS, Berlin, Germany
                        <ul>
                            <li>developed an ISDN call manager implementing an network layer state machine based on an existing link layer API</li>
                            <li>integrated the call manager into a personal communication system based on OSI stack</li>
                            <li>developed a location-based ISDN telephony service</li>
                        </ul>
                    </td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                    <td>1997 – 2002</td>
                    <td>
                        Research Assistant and Ph.D. Student, Department for Open Communication Systems (OKS), Technical University Berlin, Germany
                        <ul>
                            <li>developed 3 M.Sc. courses (management of distributed systems, broadband networks and mobile communications)</li>
                            <li>coordinated 2 main project courses (personal communication support and unified messaging)</li>
                            <li>co-managed all interactions with students for lecturers and projects</li>
                        </ul>
                    </td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                    <td>1997 – 2002</td>
                    <td>
                        Co-head of Competence Center for Open Communication Systems (OKS), FhG FOKUS, Berlin, Germany
                        <ul>
                            <li>co-developed the concept of <i>I-Centric Communications</i>, the main research focus of FOKUS for 4 years.</li>
                            <li>managed projects for developing intelligent communication sytems, unified messaging, media gateways and service personalisation– co-managed the design and development of a Unified Messaging System</li>
                            <li>designed the initial architecture for <a href="projects-fokus.html#FP5:_AlbatrOSS">IST AlbatrOSS</a></li>
                            <li>developed an E-Learning course for the <a href="projects-fokus.html#eTEN:_TEN-A">TEN-A project</a></li>
                        </ul>
                    </td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                    <td>2002 – 2003</td>
                    <td>
                        Postdoctoral Researcher, Telecommunications Software &amp; System Group (TSSG), Waterford Institute of Technology (WIT), Ireland
                        <ul>
                            <li>managed HEA basic research programme <a href="projects-tssg.html#HEA:_M-Zones">M-Zones</a></li>
                            <li>coordinated student work on research projects and strengthened M.Sc. programme</li>
                            <li>cooperated in defining the curriculum of an elective for B.Sc. programme</li>
                            <li>actively cooperated in EU Framework project proposals and running projects</li>
                        </ul>
                    </td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                    <td>2003 – 2004</td>
                    <td>
                        Investigator, Telecommunications Software &amp; System Group (TSSG), Waterford Institute of Technology (WIT), Ireland
                        <ul>
                            <li>managed HEA basic research programme <a href="projects-tssg.html#HEA:_M-Zones">M-Zones</a></li>
                            <li>participated in SFI grant to develop a PI cluster on autonomic management</li>
                            <li>cooperated in development of Ph.D. programme</li>
                            <li>actively cooperated in EU Framework project proposals and running projects</li>
                        </ul>
                    </td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                    <td>2004 – 2009</td>
                    <td>
                        Senior Investigator, Telecommunications Software &amp; System Group (TSSG), Waterford Institute of Technology (WIT), Ireland
                        <ul>
                            <li>scientific lead on architecture and modelling work in SFI PI Cluster on autonomic management (<a href="projects-tssg.html#SFI:_AMCNS">AMCNS</a>)</li>
                            <li>coordinated cooperation with industry (namely Motorola Labs, Chicago)</li>
                            <li>participated in standardisation (namely in TM Forum architecture and modelling groups and in the ACF)</li>
                            <li>designed scientific programme for HEA project <a href="projects-tssg.html#HEA:_FutureCom">FutureCom</a></li>
                            <li>supervised Ph.D. students</li>
                            <li>participated in a number of EU framework projects (namely <a href="projects-tssg.html#FP7:_AutoI">Auto-I</a>)</li>
                            <li>advised scientific work on Celtic project on autonomic management (<a href="projects-tssg.html#Celtic:_MADEIRA">MADEIRA</a>, in cooperation with Ericsson and Siemens)</li>
                            <li>consulted for a number of TSSG commercialisation projects (namely <a href="projects-tssg.html#EI:_ASyst">ASYST</a>, <a href="projects-tssg.html#EI:_I-Serv">I-Serv</a>, and <a href="projects-tssg.html#EI:_Zimbie">Zimbie</a>)</li>
                        </ul>
                    </td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                    <td>2009 – 2011</td>
                    <td>
                        Senior Research Fellow, Telecommunications Software &amp; System Group (TSSG), Waterford Institute of Technology (WIT), Ireland
                        <ul>
                            <li>Funded Investigator, Programme Manager and Leader of Work Package 2 (Architectures, Models and Algorithms) in SFI <a href="projects-tssg.html#SFI:_FAME">Strategic Research Cluster FAME</a></li>
                            <li>developing architectural artefacts and processes for business-to-network translation and semantic interoperability (in cooperation with POSTECH, HP and Cisco)</li>
                            <li>designed federation architecture (in cooperation with HP)</li>
                            <li>established distributed testbed for federated policy-based management (in cooperation with Cisco)</li>
                        </ul>
                    </td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                    <td>2011 - to date</td>
                    <td>
                        Master Engineer, Team Leader, Ericsson NM-Lab, Ericsson, Ireland
                        <ul>
                            <li></li>
                        </ul>
                    </td>
                </tr>

            </table>

        </section>
    </body>
</document>
