<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
============LICENSE_START=======================================================
Copyright (C) 2018-2019 Sven van der Meer. All rights reserved.
================================================================================
This file is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License
Full license text at https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/legalcode

SPDX-License-Identifier: CC-BY-SA-4.0
============LICENSE_END=========================================================

@author Sven van der Meer (vdmeer.sven@mykolab.com)

-->

<document>
    <properties>
        <title>SKB History</title>
        <author email="vdmeer dot sven at mykolab dot com">Sven van der Meer</author>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="SKB History">
            <p class="narrow large">
                It all started sometimes in the late 1990s, when I got my own domain (as a birthday present from very good friends).
                We started web development, first static HTML, then PHP.
                While working as a researcher and PhD student, I wanted to have a list of publications on my website.
                Later acronyms, foto collection, diaries, and other 'stuff'.
            </p>
            <p class="narrow large">
                Later in Ireland, I started programming and developing in Java.
                Github became available, and I started hosting some projects on Github.
                Those projects (PHP and Java), evolved, some I did not continue.
                The PHP backend for my site was a lot of work.
                It was very good for processing data at runtime, but it turned out to be hard to add new data (for instanc a new publication).
                So sometimes around 2011 I stopped maintaining the data, thus the whole project and site hibernated.
            </p>
            <p class="narrow large">
                In 2018 then I turned back to this problem, partially because I had an idea how to realize the whole set differently.
                for our APEX engine (and earlier in some SKB Java projects), I had experimented with the Maven Site plugin.
                I also used the Asciidoctor toolchain heavily.
                Combining both seemed a good idea.
                Then I found a way to maintain my data in a non-proprietary form (text files) that also allows to process them for other purposes (such as a website).
                And now we are here.
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
